

# PATRICK J. DALTON

WEB DEVELOPMENT & DESIGN \$\&\ 773.512.7765

• DETAILS •

773.512.7765 patrickjdalton1@gmail.com

SKILLS

HTML5 / CSS3

Angular

React

ES<sub>6</sub>

PHP (Drupal, CakePHP)

SQL (MySQL, T-SQL, SSRS)

REST/SOAP

Testing Frameworks (Jest, Mocha)

Prototyping

NoSQL (Mongo)

Templating Engines (Mustache, Handlebars, EJS, Jade)

Git

Troubleshooting / Debugging

Bash scripting

JIRA / ZenDesk

Microsoft IIS

C#.NET

ColdFusion

Postman

Package Managers (NPM, Yarn)

#### PROFILE

My varied experiences over the last 10+ years in Chicago I.T. have equipped me with a versatile toolkit, which I leverage when tackling new problems or acquiring new skills. I am humble, service-minded and constantly striving to expand my knowledge and experiences.

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Programmer III / IT Analyst at East Carolina University, Chicago, IL (Remote)

November 2022

Designing, developing and maintaining a variety of enterprise-wide internet applications housed in the university's web portal. Additional duties include:

- Managing projects / functioning as a project technical lead
- Developing specifications
- · Code testing
- · Peer code reviews
- System analysis
- Troubleshooting & maintenance + issue resolution

## Senior Application Support Analyst at American Hospital Association, Chicago, IL

January 2019 — July 2022

- Writing/maintaining complex T-SQL stored procedures/functions
- API development and design
- Building/maintaining functionality of AHA's storefront and all proximal systems
- Leading projects in the role of project manager/technical lead
- Authoring and maintaining detailed database and API documentation
- · Participating in change control processes
- Providing advanced tier-4 support to end-users

## Web Developer at BPOE USA, Chicago, IL

September 2015 — January 2019

- Building and maintaining large-scale applications for membership management (PHP, ColdFusion)
- · Refactoring and modernizing old code
- · User interface design and front-end development
- Developing wireframes / prototypes for new website functionality
- Supporting BPOE systems and users at all support tiers
- Print / email design

## Director, Technical Support at NeonCRM, Chicago, IL

June 2009 — December 2013

 Building utilities for analyzing internal performance, peak submission times, resolution cycles

- Deep usage of issue resolution and tracking software (ZenDesk, JIRA)
- Extensive technical consulting and client management
- Developing customer retention strategies
- Proposing new approaches to problems based on data-driven insights and discoveries
- Managing a team of support agents

## EDUCATION

Software Development, Northwestern University, Evanston, IL

September 2020 — March 2021

Concordia University, River Forest, IL

August 2006 — August 2009